<sec>
We next considered the effect of Ras monoubiquitination on GAP-mediated hydrolysis. 
To this end we compared the rate of GTP hydrolysis for Ras and mUbRas in the presence of the catalytic domains of two GAPs, NF1 (NF1<sup>333</sup>) and p120GAP(GAP-334)<xref>4,36</xref>.
At a GAP-to-Ras ratio of 1:500, we observed an order of magnitude increase in the rate of GTP hydrolysis for unmodified Ras relative to the intrinsic rate of GTP hydrolysis.
No increase in the rate of GTP hydrolysis was observed for mUbRas in the presence of the same GAP-to Ras ratio (<xref>Fig. 5b</xref>).
Therefore, mUbRas is insensitive to GAP-mediated regulation, similar to an oncogenic Ras<sup>G12V</sup> mutation<xref>9</xref>.
We obtained similar results using K-Ras (<xref>Supplementary Figure 6</xref>), indicating that the effects of monoubiquitination on Ras are not isoform-specific.
To verify that the differences between the enzymatic and chemical ubiquitination linkers (seven bonds and five bonds, respectively) do not alter GAP-responsiveness, we placed an additional cysteine at the c-terminus of Ubiquitin (Ubiquitin<sup>C77</sup>), thereby creating a linker one bond longer than the native linker.
We measured the rate of GAP-mediated GTP hydrolysis and observed that the response of Ras ligated to Ubiquitin<sup>C77</sup> was identical to Ras ligated to Ubiquitin<sup>G76C</sup> (<xref>Fig. 5b</xref>).
These results indicate that variations in the linker length on this scale (1-2 bonds) do not influence the sensitivity of mUbRas to GAP downregulation.
To validate the use of an in vitro system to dissect the mechanism of Ras regulation, we measured the sensitivity of mUbRas to GAP-mediated hydrolysis in a cellular reconstitution system.
We immunoprecipitated Ras from HEK293T cells and compared the sensitivity of the monoubiquitinated and unmodified fractions of Ras to regulation by GAP.
As seen in <xref>Figure 5c</xref>, monoubiquitinated K-Ras is less sensitive than the unmodified protein to GAP-mediated GTP hydrolysis.
These data support our in vitro findings that monoubiquitination increases the population of active, GTP-bound Ras through a defect in sensitivity to GAP-mediated regulation.
</sec>
