<p>
It has recently been shown that oncogenic RAS can enhance the apoptotic function of p53 via ASPP1 and ASPP2.
Mechanistically ASPP1 and ASPP2 bind RAS-GTP and potentiates RAS signalling to enhance p53 mediated apoptosis [<xref>2</xref>].
As RAS is upstream of several signalling cascades [<xref>13</xref>], we queried whether the activity of ASPP2 is regulated by the activation of a RAS-mediated signalling pathway.
One of the most studied downstream pathways of RAS signalling is the Raf-MAPK pathway.
Interestingly, we observed two conserved putative MAPK phosphorylation sites in ASPP1 and ASPP2.
The ASPP1 sites are at residues 671 and 746, and the ASPP2 sites are at residues 698 and 827 (<xref>Figure 1A</xref>).
We thus tested whether RAS activation may regulate ASPP2 phosphorylation.
An in vitro phophorylation assay was performed with a purified C-terminus fragment of ASPP2 (693-1128) containing both MAPK putative phosphorylation sites.
When compared to p38 SAPK, MAPK1 was clearly able to phosphorylate the ASPP2 fragment in vitro (<xref>Figure 1B</xref>, left and middle panels).
As shown in <xref>Figure S1</xref>, histone 2B phosphorylated by p38 SAPK had high levels of incorporated <sup>32</sup>P, suggesting that p38 SAPK was active; while under the same conditions, ASPP2 (693-1128) fragment phosphorylated by p38 SAPK had very low levels of incorporated <sup>32</sup>P, indicating that p38 SAPK is not an efficient kinase for ASPP2 phosphorylation.
The phosphorylated ASPP2 fragment by MAPK1 was digested by trypsin and fractioned on a high performance liquid chromatography (HPLC).
Each eluted fraction was measured for its radioactivity content (<xref>Figure 1B</xref>, right panel).
The fractions representing these radioactive peaks were analysed by mass spectrometry.
Of the two radioactive peaks, one represented the linker region between the GST and our ASPP2 fragment and the other corresponded to a fragment of the same mass as that containing the second putative phosphorylation site, serine 827.
Hence ASPP2 can be phosphorylated at serine 827 by MAPK1 in vitro.
</p>
